A Guide to the Records of George Bernard Lorraine, ca. 1925-1976
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
George Bernard Lorraine Records, ca. 1925-1976
Library of Virginia
31042
85.70 cubic feet; 161 Hollinger boxes, 13 file card boxes, 9 map case drawers
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Douglas LeGrand, McClean, Virginia, 15 November 1978.
Biographical/Historical Information
George Bernard Lorraine (12 January 1887- 7 January 1976), son of Charles Lorraine (1853-1939) and Martha Bohannan Lorraine (1852-1930), was a real estate broker and agent in Richmond and later Heathsville, Northumberland County, Virginia. He specialized in the sale of large private estates in Tidewater and eastern Virginia; although, he also did business in other Virginia locales and out-of-state. He was married to Estelle LeGrand Lorraine (1896-1978), and the pair had two children, John Knowles Lorraine and Margaret Lorraine Bleser. He died in Tappahannock Hospital in Essex and was interred in St. Stephens Episcopal Church Cemetery in Heathsville.
Scope and Content Information
The records, ca. 1925-1976, of George Bernard Lorraine, real estate broker and agent in the City of Richmond and Northumberland County, Virginia, consist of advertising, real estate agreements, blueprints, checks, clippings, correspondence (letters), house keys, maps, notes, obituaries, pamphlets, periodicals, photographs, plats, postcards, receipts, and surveys. They generally relate to Lorraine's real estate business, an enterprise encompassing a broad array of purchases and sales for land, businesses, houses, farms, and private estates both in Virginia and out-of-state. A significant number of these properties date their construction to the 19th, 18th and even 17th centuries. Notable properties Lorraine brokered include: Christ's Cross (Criss Cross), Dewberry, Edgewood, Keswick, Kingsmill Plantation, Locksley Hall, Mitchie Tavern, Powhite, Scotchtown, Wilton, and many Virginia Landmarks Register, National Register of Historic Properties, Historic American Building Survey, and Historic Virginia Building Survey properties.
Organization
The collection is organized into the following series and sub-series: Series I: Real estate records (Sub-series A: Virginia real estate (bulk), Sub-series B: Out-of-state real estate); Series II: Oversize (Sub- series A: Virginia real estate maps and plats (bulk), Sub-series B: Out-of-state real estate maps and plats, Sub-series C: Miscellaneous and unidentified property maps and plats); Series III: Miscellaneous business correspondence and records; Series IV: Publications; Series V: File cards.
Contents List
- Real estate records (Box 1-149)
  Arranged into Virginia and out-of-state sub-series, this series contains advertising, clippings, correspondence, deeds, maps, notes, obituaries, photographs, plats, postcards, property descriptions, surveys, and real estate agreements pertaining to properties George B. Lorraine brokered, purchased, advertised, or sold. The Virginia sub-series consists of real estate listings arranged alphabetically by county or township. The out-of-state sub-series is arranged alphabetically by state. Within both the Virginia and out-of-state sub-series, properties are arranged alphabetically first according to name. Properties without names follow second and are arranged alphabetically by property owner's surname. For most counties and states, there also exists miscellaneous letter and miscellaneous real estate listings files. The file arrangement for Series I remains consistent with the order established by the brokerage.
  Material within this series highlights the buying and selling process undertaken by Lorraine and his real estate brokerage for each property. The correspondence principally consists of letters exchanged between Lorraine's brokerage and other brokers and realtors, prospective buyers, estate administrators, property owners, real estate attorneys, and government officials. Real estate agreements between Lorraine's brokerage, owners, and buyers detail well-defined property descriptions and often accompany the correspondence, as does a profuse amount of property descriptions written for purposes of promotion and distribution to prospective buyers and advertisers. An extensive array of photographs includes exterior, interior, and aerial views of a respective plat's buildings and the adjoining landscape. Copies of these photographs often were distributed to prospective buyers and also occasionally reappear in advertisements written by Lorraine for distribution to prospective buyers, magazines and newspapers. The large bulk of advertisements does not contain images and exists in the form of newspaper clippings from the classifieds. For some of the more famed and recognized properties, clippings held in these files help to establish the history of an estate or a past owner of an estate. There are also obituaries that often denote the death of an estate owner. Smaller maps and plats also are included in these files, while larger maps and plats have been removed and placed in the oversize collection. These maps and plats often denote acreage, architectural measurements, boundaries and bordering property owners, crop and building placement, natural resources, survey information, and geographical location. Also of mention are handwritten notes detailing various business activities including phone conversations, contract negotiations, and advertising drafts. Deeds also appear for a small number of properties in this series.
  - Virginia real estate (Box 1-146)
    - Accomack County (Box 1-2)
      - Accomac Hotel: Jones Brothers, 1950, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Andua: J. Milton Mason, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Bellevue: Mrs. William P. Bell, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Cobb's Island: E.B. Cobb, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Corbin Hall or Chincoteague Farm: J. Grover Rowley and Eva C. Handy, 1934-1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Corbin Hall: R.C. Mackay, 1948-1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Corbin Hall: R.C. Mackay, 1948-1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Evergreen Plantation: Stevens & Company, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Finney Farm: John W. Robertson, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Half Moon Island: G. Walter Mapp, 1935-1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Hill Farm: J.S. Mathias, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Hollybrook Farm: George D. Deere, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Mockon Island: Larimer A. Cushman, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Oceanview: George E. Jones, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Rose Cottage: Reverend M.R. Barton, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Snugly: Charles B. Mears, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Walston Farm: Charles F. Russell, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Warwick: J.D. Martensen, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Wesley: 70 acres, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Ames, Walter: 1934 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Besold, C. of Eastern Shore Lodge: 1934 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Brookbank, James H.: 1934 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Chandler, J.W.: 1934 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Cooke, M. Clifton: 30 acres, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Darwin, Geraldine G.: 535 acres, 82 acres, and marshland, 1960, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Ellerman, George D.: 40 acres, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Hall, Mrs. James: 1934 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Harrell, W.R.: 1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Justis, Willie and G.W.: 170 1/2 acres, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Mackay, Ralph S.: 1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Mapp, J. Brooks: 1400 acres, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Mapp, Mrs. W.B.: 476 acres, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Markham, G.G.: 140 acres, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Martin, S.K.: 611 acres, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Matthews, W.H.: 1935 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Metompkin Bank and Trust Company: 395 acres, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Nock, L.W.: 172 acres, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Nottingham, Louise Jarvis: 1 1/2 acres, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Powell, Bernard R.: 328 acres, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Spence, Mrs. Vernon L.: home on Tangier Island, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Stevens, Captain W.C.: 42 acres, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Witham, M.E.: 1934 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Miscellaneous letter file: 1939, 1960-1962, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Albemarle County (Box 3-8)
      - Argyle: Harry Langhorne, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Barksdale: W.A. Barksdale, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Barracks: Mary Maury Mayo, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Bel Aire: 447 acres, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Bellair: Leigh R. Walker, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Belmont Orchard: R.L. Miles, 1930-1932 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Ben-Coolyn: W.B. Bogert, 1936-1948 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Birdwood: Henry L. Fonda and J. Dewitt Wilde, 1935-1939 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Boxwood: W. Alonzo Rinehart, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Branchlands: Dr. H.P. Johnson, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Brook Hill: G.A. Dunlop, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Brookfield Farm: 125 acres, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Canaan Farm: P.H. Faulconer, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Castiglione: J. Frank Payne, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Castiglione: Charles J. Symington, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Castle Hill: n.d. (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Chester: G.M. Dillard, 1936-1938 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Cliffside: Virginia Moore, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Clover Hill Farm: Thomas D. Grinnell, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Colle: F.L. Mehring, 1933-1938 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Commander Reid or Rawle Farm: Greenbrier Joint Stock Land Bank, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Compton: Stevens & Company (realtors), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Cottage: L.C. Burt, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Craigmillar: James B. Gilmer, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Dunham: Rhoda B. Beirnes, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Eagles Nest: Charles B. Livers, 1933-1934 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - East Bellmont: Mrs. Harrison Taylor and H.C. Huffer, 1938-1947 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Ednam: Marjorie Copps, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - Edgemont: Graham Clark, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Edgeworth: Mrs. Bruce P. Smith, 1932-1943 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - Ellerslie: William T. Stevens and Roy Wheeler (realtors), 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Esmont Farm or Old Esmont: Laura S. Lane, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Estouteville: Mrs. George A. Randolph, 1936-1943 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Fall Field Farm: Jess H. Wilson, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Forest Lodge: 750 acres, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Fox Ridge Farm: Polly P. McGavock (realtor), 1952 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Franklin Farm: Henry McComb Bush, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Franklin: Stevens & Company (realtors), 1943 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Greenfield Farm: James J. Riley, Jr., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Green Mountain: Mrs. Charles A. Miller, 1936-1938 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Greenfields: Mrs. Harry Langhorne, 1938-1947 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Guthrie Hall: T.S. Duncan, 1931-1936 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Guthrie Hall: Louise Jenkins Kinney, 1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Hampstead: Mrs. Horatio L. Small, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Happy Creek Lodge: Mrs. T.E. Quick, 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Hardindale: Roy Wheeler (realtor), 1938 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Hardware River Farm: Potomac Joint Stock Land Bank, 1932-1939 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Hardware River Farm and Turkey Run Farm: E.L. Bailey, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Hatton Grange: J.W.M. Witten, 1934-1936 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Hatton Grange: C.A. Blair, 1949-1952 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Jefferson Mill: J.A. Moulton, 1935-1955 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Kenwood: Edward M. Watson, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Keswick: Thomas Walker Page, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Kinross Farm formerly Repose: Paul E. Hunt, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Lewis Mountain or Kearny Estate: John Watts Kearny, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Limestone: Mrs. George H. Whitten, 1941-1947 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Linden: B.C. Sutherland, 1938-1942 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Locust Dale Inn: Mrs. George S. Goodloe, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Locust Grove: 269 acres, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Locust Shade: Elizabeth Tompkins, 1936-1942 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Lone Oak Farm: T.N. Steinbland, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Manor House: 1947 acres, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Marlewood Hall: Dr. Herbert Chase, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Mirador: Mrs. Ronald Tree, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Merrie Mill: Percy Montague, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Michie Tavern: Vestal Thomas Grigg, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Montesano: F.H. Lewis, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Monticola: George Barkley (realtor), 1961 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Mount Fair: Edmund S. Campbell and F.H. Schroeder (realtor), 1936-1950 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Mount Israel Farm: Myrtle Foster, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Mount Walla: H.C. Lowry, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Mount Warren: Stuart Morgan, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Mountain Hollow Orchard: 270 acres, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Mountain View: 443 acres, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - New Dominion Orchards: 277 acres, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Norriden Place: E.M. Hammond, 1934-1938 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Northwoods: Mrs. N.E. Murray, 1943-1946 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Oakhurst: 147 acres, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Oakhurst: Alex A. Galto, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Oakleigh and Port of Ferry: Roy Wheeler (realtor), 1959 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Oaks: H.F. Nickel, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Old Hall: Louisa Beal, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Old Woodville, Old Rector and Rosedale: Alan McFarlane, 1936-1938 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - O'Neill Orchard: C.T. O'Neill, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Orchards: Samuel B. Woods, 1931-1937 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Overlook: Roy Wheeler (realtor), 1937 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - Overlook (guest home): Mrs. Nelson Richards, 1947-1949 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Owatunka: Powhatan Wyndham Robertson, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Pantops Farm: William R. Stevens, 1948-1949 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Piedmont Manor: A.M. Morrison, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Piedmont Manor: Howard Friend, 1934-1952 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Plain Dealing: John J. Sample, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Porter: 80 acres, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Red Field or Kidder: Delos B. Kidder, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Red Hills: Polly P. McGavock (realtor), 1949 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Refuge: Mrs. Marian McKay, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Repose: 230 acres, 1927-1939 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Richland: Charles E. Blue, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - River Lawn: Elizabeth Reaves Snead, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Riverdale: Winship Nunnally, 1938-1942 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Riverhill Farm: R.E. Mesnard, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Rivermont: Theodore R. Wood, 1946-1949 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Riverview: Irene Briggs, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Rock Hill Orchards: Clark C. Wade, 1938-1941 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Rockwell Farm: F.R. Chamberlain, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Rose Hill: Clayton W. Williams, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Royal Acres: John C. Inge, 1948-1950 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Rugby Farm: 453 acres, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Sedge Hill: Mrs. E.H. DeJarnette, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Shadow: S.R. Durrett, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Stump Island Farm: J.F. Odle, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Sunny Side: James M. Barr, Jr., 1935-1938 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Talkwood: Louis Chauvenat, 1936-1938 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Tally-ho-farm: James J. Riley, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Temple Hill: F.H. Schroeder, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Thomas Jefferson Inn: Thomas Jefferson Corporation, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Tiverton: Mrs. Fred Owsley, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Totier: Stuart Morgan, 1947-1949 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Tucked-Away: L.G. Herring, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Tufton: Robert L. McElroy, 1937-1943 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Tufton: George H. Barkley, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Underhill Farm: C.B. Baker, 1938-1950 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Viewmont: Roberts Coles, Jr., 1936-1938 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Villa Crawford: August Heid, 1936-1942 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Wakefield: L.A. Dovel, 1936-1938 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - West Cairns: Robert L. McElroy, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Windsor: V.R. Shackleford, 1938-1940 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Woodlands: J.R. Wingfield, Jr., 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Woodland: Dr. Will Walter, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Allen, R.D.: 1938 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Burkholder, R.S. (realtor): 300 acres, 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Burruss, Elmer E.: 1940 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Critzer, Mr.: store and home, 1952-1954 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Davis, R.B.: n.d. (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Evans, C.T.: 50 acres, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Foster, M.H.: 228 acres, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Johns, V.M.: 150 acres, 1932-1934 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Kinderman, Dr. Harold: 40 acres, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - McGavock, Polly P. (realtor): 150 acres, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Pearman, Mrs. M.M.: 1957 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Pope, W.M. and Ray W. Warrick: farm, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - Pugh, J.G.: store, drive-in theater and house, 1947-1951 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Raines, M.L.: 327 acres, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Schroeder, F.H. (realtor): 320 acres, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Schroeder, F.H. (realtor): 1951 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Schroeder, F.H. (realtor): 18 acres, 1947-1949 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Simpson, Henry B.: 1933 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Stearns, Mrs. John N.: 500 acres, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Wickline, H.B.: 252 acres, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Wood, C.E.: 75 acres, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous letter file: 1931-1963 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings: A-E (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings: E-M (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings: O-Z (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Alexandria (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Studio: F.E. Breese, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Alleghany County (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Peyton, T.G.: 4 acres, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Amelia County (Box 9, Folder 3-10)
      - Glenmore: H.W. Gill, 1964, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Redmoor: Lewis K. Denning, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Selma: 450 acres, 1942-1944 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Selma: Karl F. Snearer, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Woodland: H.M. Williams, 1937-1944 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Farrar, Joseph B.: 236 acres, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous letter file: 1949 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Amherst County (Box 9, Folder 11-18)
      - Islington: W.B. Clark (realtor), 1955 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Morris Place: August Herd, 1937-1941 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Skyland: W.H. Hickson, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - White Hall: Caroline H. Garland, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Coleman, B.B.: 200 acres, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - John L. Mosby: 7500 acres, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous letter file: 1938-1939 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Appomattox County (Box 9-10)
      - Cynbaren Farms: Mrs. Warren Corning, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Eldon or Hillendale: H.D. Flood, 1937-1943 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Eldon or Hillendale: 1950 (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - Vallelindo Farm: J.W. Smith, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Harwood, E.W.: 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Lunsford, A.L.: 1951-1953 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous letter file: n.d. (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Arlington (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
      - Rixey, John J.: 120 acres, 1938-1939 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Augusta County (Box 10-11)
      - Belvidere Farm: Margaret E. McCue, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Locust Isle: Charles C. Rainey, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Merrifield Farm: J.L. Witz, 1937-1945 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Montezuma: J. Wesley Taylor, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Parmalee House: J.B. Parmalee, 1942-1943 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Silver Brook: Thomas F. Clemmer, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Ritchie Farm: Anne Ritchie Wright, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Sugarloaf Farm: Dr. W.D. Pedigo, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Swannanoa: Swannanoa Development Corporation, 1927-1944 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Swannanoa: Swannanoa Development Corporation, 1939-1944 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Anthony, Wilbur P.: 121 acres, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Bell, Hugh B.: 1949 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - Doenges, C.W., Jr.: 3 1/4 acres, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - Knowles, A. Lee: 345 acres, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - Loving, T.A.: 200 acres, 1945-1947 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Marion, Wallace W.: 1948 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Roberts, Mrs. George H.: 32 acres, 1952-1953 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Schroeder, F.H. (realtor): 1 acre, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Thompson, W.W.: 1946 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Tilson, W.E. & Son: 800 acres, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Bath County (Box 11, Folder 8-10)
      - Hidden Valley Farm: Chase National Bank, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Wetoo: Cook & Jackson (realtors), 1949 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Bedford County (Box 11, Folder 11-17)
      - Bedford Alum Springs: M. Eichelbaum, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Cattle-otter farm: T. Nelson Boswell, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Creswell Farm: F.H.T. Walton, 1935-1937 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Creswell Farm: Joseph Schwerin, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Otterburn: Garnett G. Ballard, 1933-1934 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Miscellaneous letter file: 1931-1938, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Bland County (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Botetourt County (Box 12, Folder 2-4)
      - Botetourt Hotel: Mrs. Terry H. Brooks, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous letter file: 1944, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Brunswick County (Box 12, Folder 5-9)
      - Bentfield: 750 acres, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Brunswick Plantation: R.A. Harris, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Roquin: Virginia L. Bragg, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous letter file: 1939 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Buckingham County (Box 12, Folder 10-29)
      - Algoma: G.W. Main, 1935-1942 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Bear Garden: Carey Shipp, 1938-1954 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Clairmont: L.B. Horgen, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Dungannon: Mrs. Kale L. Bruno, 1936-1940 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Gold Hill: W.L. Putney, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Greenway Court: John Stewart Walker (realtor), 1941 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Hermitage: A.F. Nicholas, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - Merrywood: Rosalie E. Stevens, 1950-1958 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Mount Ida: Joint Stock Land Bank, 1932-1934 (Box 12, Folder 18)